Guide to the Fred Ross papers M0812
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series F. Audio & Transcripts (444 tapes)
  - Subseries: Audiocassettes
    - Audiocassettes, 1978-1984
      - 9/3/80. Gen. Mtg. Sta Paula, Arturo Rodriguez leading (Box 40 (OS), Folder 303)
      - 8/27/80. Mtg. of Comite de Cabeza in Sta Paula - Arturo Rodriguez leading (Box 40 (OS), Folder 304)
      - [August 1980?]. Mtg. with "Comite de Cabeza" in Sta Paula - Arturo Rodriguez leading (Box 40 (OS), Folder 305)
      - [1980?]. Unemployment (Box 40 (OS), Folder 306)
      - 10/26/80. Unemp. beginning and beginning of training session (Box 40 (OS), Folder 307)
      - 3/22/82. Unidentified woman interviewing Fred Ross. Poor sound (Box 40 (OS), Folder 308)
      - March 22, 1982. Fred Ross. (Box 40 (OS), Folder 309)
      - 7/19/82. Survival Institute (Box 40 (OS), Folder 310)
      - 7/19/82. Survival Institute (Box 40 (OS), Folder 311)
      - 7/19/82. Survival Institute (Box 40 (OS), Folder 312)
      - 2/10/83. Feinstein (Box 40 (OS), Folder 313)
      - 2/10/83. Feinstein. Preparing the pitch, Gibs House Meeting (Box 40 (OS), Folder 314)
      - 2/10/83. Feinstein. (Box 40 (OS), Folder 315)
      - 2/19/83. Fred and pt time [illeg.]. Gib explains. Mathew HM, Gib gives HM (Box 40 (OS), Folder 316)
      - 6/16 [1983?]. Tr. Session - Feinstein Reelection (Box 40 (OS), Folder 317)
      - 6/16 [1983?]. [Tr. Session - Feinstein Reelection?] (Box 40 (OS), Folder 318)
      - [6/16/83. Tr. Session - Feinstein Reelection?] (Box 40 (OS), Folder 319)
      - 5/2/84, Carmel. Fred Ross org. (Box 40 (OS), Folder 320)
      - 5/2/84. Fred Ross org. (Box 40 (OS), Folder 321)
      - 5/3/84. Carmel session (Box 40 (OS), Folder 322)
      - 5/4/84, Carmel. Fred Ross Hs Mtg. proper. Ellis rap (Box 40 (OS), Folder 323)
      - [May 1984?], Carmel. Discussion of Ellis rapp [sic]. Meeting after Mtg. - to put pressure on and make friends (Box 40 (OS), Folder 324)
      - [May 1984, Carmel?]. Post Mortem. Jackie goes for $! Katie and taking phone off hook. Vibes - Post Mortem. Jackie gets "brusque" and feels OK about it! (Box 40 (OS), Folder 325)
      - May 16 [1984?], Carmel. Post Mortem (Box 40 (OS), Folder 326)
      - May 16 [1984?], Carmel. Post Mortem (Box 40 (OS), Folder 327)
      - [May 1984, Carmel?]. Vibes and Post Mortem (Box 40 (OS), Folder 328)
    - Audiocassettes, 1985-1987, undated
      - 4/27/85. Fred Sr. Tape #1. Mike Ganley. Japanese Americans (Box 41 (OS), Folder 329)
      - 4/27/85. Fred Ross Sr. Tape #2. Mike Ganley. Alinsky, Citrus Belt. Origin of CSO (Box 41 (OS), Folder 330)
      - 4/27-4/28 1985. Fred Ross Sr. Tape # 3. Ross reads "What happened to Pete." Bloody Xmas. (Box 41 (OS), Folder 331)
      - 4/30-5/1 '85. Fred Ross Sr. Tape # 6 (Box 41 (OS), Folder 332)
      - 5/1/85. Fred Ross Sr. Tape #7 (Box 41 (OS), Folder 333)
      - 5/1-5/2/85. Fred Ross Sr. Tape #8 (Box 41 (OS), Folder 334)
      - 5/2/85. Fred Ross Sr. Tape #9 (Box 41 (OS), Folder 335)
      - 7/4/87. Fred Ross. Please return to Bill Beachy (Box 41 (OS), Folder 336)
      - 7/4/87. Fred Ross. Please return to Bill Beachy (Box 41 (OS), Folder 337)
    - Undated tapes by probable year
      - [1975?]. La Paz Elect. Org Cass #11 (Box 41 (OS), Folder 338)
      - [1975?]. La Paz 2/75 (?) Waves of Immigrants (Box 41 (OS), Folder 339)
      - [1975?]. 2nd session at La Paz (Box 41 (OS), Folder 340)
      - [1977?]. Boston. Greg Costello. Mary Ann and friend from Florida. Mike Guanel [?] - chart of community. (Box 41 (OS), Folder 341)
      - [1977?]. Boston - HM practice. Max - practices. [Illeg.] and Chris practice (Box 41 (OS), Folder 342)
      - [1977?]. PV Chris C. Mark - Hs. Mtg. Alice (Box 41 (OS), Folder 343)
      - [1977?]. Mark (Box 41 (OS), Folder 344)
      - [1977?]. Max HM - last section (Box 41 (OS), Folder 345)
      - [1977?]. Fred Ross (Box 41 (OS), Folder 346)
      - [1978?]. Arvin Mig. Camp - Woodie [sic] Guthrie. War - Braceros [illeg.] WRA - ACRR - San Bernardino, Ruth [illeg.] (Box 41 (OS), Folder 347)
      - [1978?]. Cesar - Oxnard - carrot topping episode (Box 41 (OS), Folder 348)
      - [1980?]. 2/2. Voter Reg. Org'g Drive. (Box 41 (OS), Folder 349)
      - [1985?]. Ellie (Box 41 (OS), Folder 350)
      - [1985?]. Ellie (Box 41 (OS), Folder 351)
      - [1985?]. Ellie (Box 41 (OS), Folder 352)
      - [1985?]. Ellie (Box 41 (OS), Folder 353)
      - [1985?]. [Ellie?] (Box 41 (OS), Folder 354)
      - [1985?]. Post Mortem. The blow up over pressure at end of 1st 2 weeks (Box 41 (OS), Folder 355)
      - [1985?]. Art Auction and Fund Raising (Box 41 (OS), Folder 356)
      - [1985?]. The Blow up on end of "Pressure," Post Mortem Carmel (Box 41 (OS), Folder 357)
      - [1985?]. May 18 - Post Mortem Carmel (Box 41 (OS), Folder 358)
      - [1985?]. May 18 - Post Mortem Carmel (Box 41 (OS), Folder 359)
      - [1985?]. May 22 - Carmel Freeze Vibe Session. Post Mortem (Box 41 (OS), Folder 360)
      - [1985?]. June 1 - Carmel Post Mortem. May 31 (Box 41 (OS), Folder 361)
    - Audiocassettes, undated 1
      - Historia de Santa Maria. Canciones y poemas. Una hora, historia [illeg.] (Box 41 (OS), Folder 362)
      - CORE Post Mortem. Boston - Guy, Mark, Alice, etc. (Box 41 (OS), Folder 363)
      - P.V. Prep. for PV - Spouse. Out-line - sm. talk - church? Job? making friends - synopsis to give to host. We map the battle of the phone. Ross gives P.V. good - and host's phone call (Box 41 (OS), Folder 364)
      - Phoning - Alameda. Eden - Org with Lois. (Box 41 (OS), Folder 365)
      - Phoning and P.V. 1st Personal Visit. HM Outline - CC at Burciaga's house (Box 41 (OS), Folder 366)
      - House Mtg - charismatic leading. Nancy - Visalia - Sadie. Wash DC. Casa Blanca - learning to hold Hs Mtgs (Box 41 (OS), Folder 367)
      - Rick. Wash SC - PV and Hs Mtg (Box 41 (OS), Folder 368)
      - CSO - 1952 - Cesar and beginning NFWA org. CSO '52 to Org. NFWA. New York - Bloody Xmas. History "Okis" to Cesar. (Box 41 (OS), Folder 369)
      - Following Hs Mtg outline to victory in grapes. Following Hs Mtg Outline - Lettuce Strike 1970-70 [?] Calif Sup Court Ruling 1972 (Box 41 (OS), Folder 370)
      - almost inaudible (Box 41 (OS), Folder 371)
      - 5-6 (Box 41 (OS), Folder 372)
      - The House Meeting. The 1st Person (Box 41 (OS), Folder 373)
      - Bobby Debale [?] (Box 41 (OS), Folder 374)
      - La Paz Elect Org (Box 41 (OS), Folder 375)
      - CM (7) Ross (Box 41 (OS), Folder 376)
      - II Ross (Box 41 (OS), Folder 377)
      - Tape III (Box 41 (OS), Folder 378)
      - Tape V (Box 41 (OS), Folder 379)
      - Simulated phone calls. To Steffan's report on simulated phone calls (Box 41 (OS), Folder 380)
      - Part of prep for P.V., reports on sim'd P.V.'s, Paul, etc. Dolores explains Gallo-Teamo[illeg.] contract (Box 41 (OS), Folder 381)
      - Prep for Hs Mtgs. Ability to admit we flubbed the dub. Ploting [sic] out the "Hs Mtg" per se. Taking the blame, yourself. How to avoid organizing for other organizers (Box 41 (OS), Folder 382)
    - Audiocassettes, undated 2
      - Cesar - Hs Mtg. with F. Wrks to dream[illeg.] El Malcreado [sic]. Cesar on "Organizing" and fouding of NFWA to big grape strike (Box 42 (OS), Folder 383)
      - Dolores on Big Strike to Gallo 1967 UFW (Box 42 (OS), Folder 384)
      - 9/27/74. Lucia and Fred Ross. Gallo 1970 to Cesar's fast. Beginning boycott - Beginning Lettuce strike 1970 (Box 42 (OS), Folder 385)
      - 1/75. Strike of '73 - Teamo violence girl blinded. Gallo Strike - 1973 to "17 shot - 200 hospitalized" - 1973 strke. (Box 42 (OS), Folder 386)
      - Fri evening. After the House Mtg (Box 42 (OS), Folder 387)
      - Florida 72-75 also NLRB fights. Traiing Session. (Box 42 (OS), Folder 388)
      - Barbara Macry House Mtg. (Box 42 (OS), Folder 389)
      - Trip to Fresno (Box 42 (OS), Folder 390)
      - Starting a training session for "the book" - "Getting" ready to organize - USC and church - illeg. - Milligan - carrots (Box 42 (OS), Folder 391)
      - 10/10, LA. Ross, Bobbie and Ken - sim'd 1st visits. (Box 42 (OS), Folder 392)
      - 10/10. LA. Ross. Why Teamos are in Agric and Vs [?] UFW. Beginning of background. Hs Mtg outline. Hist of Teamos i. ag and why in this situation (Box 42 (OS), Folder 393)
      - Cesar and Chicano labor leaders. Cesar in Madera [illeg.] During Fast (Box 42 (OS), Folder 394)
      - Oakland. Bad tape (Box 42 (OS), Folder 395)
      - Field Office Session (Box 42 (OS), Folder 396)
      - Ross and Vivian - New organizers don't know themsleves or the people. Org of LA CSO. Roybal. Cesar and beginning of Long March, 1966. Saint [illeg.] (Box 42 (OS), Folder 397)
      - NY. Dave Koeler. Mary Mc. Core Group Mtg. P.M. (Box 42 (OS), Folder 398)
      - Planning the Hs Mtg - Gallo emphasis to discussion of NLRA. Following Hs Meeting Outline to Cesar and fried chicken story. Doroles story re Cesar's hardships (Box 42 (OS), Folder 399)
      - 1st 60 sec spot recruitment, 2nd announcement. History - Gallo following Hs Mtg Outline (Box 42 (OS), Folder 400)
      - NLRA. Waves of immigrants [illeg.] (Box 42 (OS), Folder 401)
      - Boston HM. Role Playing Pt. 2. Marc [?], Alice, Iris [?], Max (Box 42 (OS), Folder 402)
      - 4/28. Tape 2 - Boston Session. The Outline to Fast (Box 42 (OS), Folder 403)
      - Tape 3 Boston Session. Pt 1, 2, and 3 of Outline (Box 42 (OS), Folder 404)
      - Tape 5 Boston. House Mtg Practice. Alice, Marc, Max. Wk on HEI [?] Outline to So. West Corner Delano Movie (Box 42 (OS), Folder 405)
      - Tape 6 - HM practice. Post Mortems on sim'd HM's - Chris Donoughue role player CMLI critique. Sacrifice beginning of fried chicken (Box 42 (OS), Folder 406)
      - Tape 7 Boston. Fried chicken - service center. Fast Boston. Wkg on outline - Florida (Box 42 (OS), Folder 407)
      - Tape 8 Boston. Wkg on outline - 1st MA graduate Delano High School. Irv runs sim'd HM. Joy gives $5.00 to Cesar (Box 42 (OS), Folder 408)
      - Chicago. (Box 42 (OS), Folder 409)
      - Fred Ross. House Meeting. Discussion on H. Mtg. - content - final appeal for help for other Hs Mtgs etc. More discussion on H. Mtg. content by Jan P., Jim and Vivien, Andy Coe (Box 42 (OS), Folder 410)
      - Fred Ross. House Meeting. April 3 - Review of previous day. Violence. Teamo's - Valdez - H. Hasawara (Box 42 (OS), Folder 411)
      - Feb 1. CORE group prep Oakland. Debbie on NSO agenda. (Box 42 (OS), Folder 412)
      - Core group - Oakland. Prep for NSOrg 1st part of agenda. Dan Bacar - logistics (Box 42 (OS), Folder 413)
      - NSO discussion. Wash DC core group (Box 42 (OS), Folder 414)
      - Oak Training. Post Morteming (Box 42 (OS), Folder 415)
      - House Meeting. Steffan and Frank Ortiz Hs Mtgs. Dolores (Box 42 (OS), Folder 416)
      - Cesar with Dick Muster [?] (Box 42 (OS), Folder 417)
      - Empty cassette case labelled 1-2 (Box 42 (OS), Folder 418)
      - Empty cassette case labelled 9-10 (Box 42 (OS), Folder 419)
      - Unlabelled (Box 42 (OS), Folder 420)
      - Unlabelled (Box 42 (OS), Folder 421)
      - Unlabelled (Box 42 (OS), Folder 422)
      - Mi[illeg.] Ybarra Hs Mtg (Box 42 (OS), Folder 423)
      - Politics Clint Reilly (Box 42 (OS), Folder 424)
      - Putting HM together. 174 on - Post Mortem after night of phoning - Jay and Iris. Role playing HM with Jap [Jay?] (Box 42 (OS), Folder 425)
      - Larry HM. Larry and Iris (Box 42 (OS), Folder 426)
      - Not used - bum tape (Box 42 (OS), Folder 427)
      - Tues., May 15, Carmel. Post Mortem (Box 42 (OS), Folder 428)
      - Drum Major (365) Memphis. March on Washington 8/63. A.D. Randolph, W. Reuther [?], R. Wilkins (506) "I Have a Dream" (Box 42 (OS), Folder 429)
      - Tape 1, Carmel [written in dark ink on black cassette] (Box 42 (OS), Folder 430)
      - Discussion of Hs Mtgs just prior to video taping. From 1st Hs Mtg to A.W. 1970 - Daily staff mtgs - self organization. Analysis of org's day etc. (Box 42 (OS), Folder 431)
      - Bach, etc. MARR. Neat music (Box 42 (OS), Folder 432)
      - Empty cassette case labelled "Post Mortem. Vibes session and maybe Post Mortem. Heavy set guy with German last name. Jackie - Katie, Mark" (Box 42 (OS), Folder 433)
      - Empty cassette case labelled "Coleridge-Taylor: Petite Suite de Concert, Etc. (SXLP 30123, EMI)" (Box 42 (OS), Folder 434)
      - Unlabelled (Box 42 (OS), Folder 435)
      - Unlabelled (Box 42 (OS), Folder 436)
- Series G: Miscellaneous (.5 linear feet)
  Box 19A contains photocopies of damaged material segregated during original processing. This material was not reordered, and may fit into other relevant series or files. Box 19B contains the originals, and is closed for research.
  - Gallo strike, 1975 (Box 19A, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence [personal & professional], 1930-1974 (Box 19A, Folder 2)
  - CSO interviews, Hanford, California, 1959 (Box 19A, Folder 3)
  - Giumarra vs. UFW injunction [photocopy]; Delano strike flier; UFW Spanish bulletins, 1967 (Box 19A, Folder 4)
  - War Relocation Authority memoranda, etc., 1944-1945 (Box 19A, Folder 5)
  - Clippings; UFW pamphlet re: Perelli-Minetti 1966 (Box 19A, Folder 6)
  - Ross - History of the Farmworker Movement 10/1974 [also Box 16 Folder 11]; training materials - house meeting outline; memo re: DiGiorgio (Box 19A, Folder 7)
  - Handwritten notes, list of names 1962 [typescript fragments on back of some sheets] (Box 19A, Folder 8)
  - Annotated typescript excerpts [photocopy; possibly Cesar Chavez memoir??] (Box 19A, Folder 9)
  - Mimeograph in Spanish [illegible] (Box 19A, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous: Daisy Ross obit draft; poem; 1 p. annotated typescript [related to above?] (Box 19A, Folder 11)
  - Invoices, etc., 1969-1970 (Box 19A, Folder 12)
  - ORIGINALS RESTRICTED DUE TO CONDITION SEE BOX 19A FOR COPIES (Box 19B)
- Series H. Accession 2015
  - Photograph of Bishop Donahue, Stockton, undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Ross letters to father, 1920 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Ross report cards, letter from USC schoolmate (1970), 1928-1935 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Ross, Lillian (et al.). The Argonauts (Modern Age Books) [photocopy], 1940 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Library of Congress American Memory website: "Lafe" Todd, Arvin & Shafter camps 1940 [printouts] (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Chavez Daily Reports, 1954-1957 (Box 47, Folders 1-19)
  - Ventura CSO fiesta planning, 1959 (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Arizona/Guadalupe clippings, etc., 1964-1970 (Map-folder 49, Folder 2)
  - CSO clippings, Records of CSO Deputy Registrars (Map-folder 49, Folder 3)
  - Farm Security Agency (FSA) Efficiency Report, 1941 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Ross draft classification, 1944 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - War Relocation Authority (WRA), 1943-1946 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - scrapbook of clippings, photos, memoranda, etc., 1949-1957 (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - South Gate Tenant Council to Ross, 1946 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Alinsky - Ross correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 46, Folders 1-2)
  - Ross interview transcript re: Japanese-American Relocation, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - American Council on Race Relations [photocopies from University of Chicago], 1946-1947 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - McCall's reprint on Alinsky, Back of the Yard (Map-folder 49, Folder 1)
  - Council for Human Rights Anti-Klan Rally, 1946 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - "The Least 'Un" - Ross FSA poem, 1951 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Ross, Fred. Get Out If You Can: The Saga of Sal Si Puedes (California Federation for Civic Unity), 1953 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Los Angeles CSO, Gilbert Anaya correspondence etc., 1954; Many sheets in poor condition (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Chavez to Delgadillo [photocopy], 1954 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Ross to Chavez [photocopies], 1954-1955 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - CSO documents and clippings, 1954-1960 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - CSO Second National Convention, Los Angeles, 1955 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Stockton CSO, Louis Gonzalez correspondence, etc., 1957-1985 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - CSO Reporter, 1958 (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Oxnard clipping, 1959 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Alinsky testimony - Commission on Civil Rights Housing Hearing, 1959 (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Day Planner, 1959 (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Mother to Ross, 1959; Partially legible due to water damage. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Burton - Assembly Bill no. 5, 1961 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - CSO Executive Board minutes, 1962-03-16 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Wife To Ross, 1964 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Di Giorgio pro-Teamster flier; UFW fliers; Newsweek article, 1966 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - El Malcriado Vol. II No.5, 1968 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Chavez presidential endorsements, 1968 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Chavez statement following fast, 1968-03-10 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Gallo election campaign notebook, 1975; Item is musty due to prior exposure to moisture (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Ross testimony - ALRB hearing re: UFW vs. Gallo, 1978 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Ross 75th Birthday, 1985 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - UFW 25th Anniversary Benefit program, 1987-05-23 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Ross 80th Birthday, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Weatherwax to Ross, Jr., 1992 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Ross memorial, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Ross memorial statements: Jimmy Herman (ILWU); Joe Castorena (LA CSO), 1992 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Ross memorial statement: Cesar Chavez, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Pelosi - Congressional recognition, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - John Dunne quote, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Ross memorial clippings, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Ross clippings (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Ellie Cohen documentary proposal, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Michael J. Ganley, Fred Ross: Portrait of a Hero drafts, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Nancy Elliot recollections, 2003 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Axioms (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - FBI Freedom of Information Request, 1995 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Ross, Conquering Goliath draft (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Ross, The Di Giorgio Story annotated draft (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Chavez, The Fresno - Madera - Bakersfield Story March 1954-June 1956 annotated draft (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Chavez, The Oxnard Story parts I-V 1958-1962 annotated draft (Box 45, Folders 9-10)
  - Chavez clippings (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - San Bernadino CSO, Imperial, 1954 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Alinsky - Ross correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 46, Folders 4-5)
  - CSO Consolidation, 1957-1958 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Alinsky - Ross correspondence, 1957-1964 (Box 46, Folders 7-14)
  - Alinsky - Ross correspondence - incomplete, undated (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - CSO Alinsky - Ross miscellaneous (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Misc. notes, memoranda, minutes - CSO, UFW, etc. (Box 47, Folder 22)
  - Audio reel #12. Fred Ross, Cesar Chavez, Dr. McCann [sticker on reel: May 7 - Part 2 - Dr. McCann + Part 1 - Fred Ross] (Box 48, Reel 1)
  - Audio reel #20. Cesar - Jan.1, 1966 - The March - April 66 (Box 48, Reel 2)
  - Audio Reel #22. Blanca Gomez and Cesar Chavez, 1967-01-18 (Box 48, Reel 3)
  - Audio Reel #24. Reel 2 - Fred Ross & Cesar Chavez. May 7. Transcribed - 10/11/65 [sticker on reel: May 7 - Fred Ross. Reel #2], 1965 (Box 48, Reel 4)
  - Audio Reel #25. Fred Ross & Cesar Chavez, Arizona Training Program, 1960-05 (Box 48, Reel 5)
  - Audiocassette: Ed. Session, 1971-09-27 (Box 48, Cassette 6)
  - Audiocassette: Beginning of Fresno Bee Clippings Aug.65 - June 2, 1966; Fresno Bee UWAC Clippings 6/3/66 - 8/8/67, 1965-1967 (Box 48, Cassette 7)